(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T04:43:27.058530",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はあ…今日も暑いね…
Phew... It's so hot today...
今日しちゃってからというものは毎日が退屈で、早く配信したいな…
Ever since I did that, every day has been so boring, I want to stream soon...
こうやって海を眺めるのも、飽きてきたで。
I'm getting tired of just staring at the ocean like this.
みこさん、お久し振りです。
Miko-san, long time no see.
神です。電脳桜神社の神です。
I am a god. The god of Cyber Sakura Shrine.
はあ…すっかり忘れてたよ！もう設定というか概念になりかけてたで。
Phew... I completely forgot! I was almost turning into just a concept.
設定とか言わないで！！！
Don't call it a setting!
あなたは《巫女》なんですから、つかえる神がいるのも当たり前ですよ！
You're a shrine maiden, so of course you have a god serving you!
みこか。今はみこエリートアイドルとしてホロライブで頑張ってるからさあ、すっかり忘れてたよ。
Miko... Right now I'm working hard as an elite idol in Hololive, so I completely forgot.
もうアイドルが本業みたいなもんだよね。
Idoling is basically my main job now anyway.
ところで、何で久しぶりにこっちに来たの？
By the way, why did you come here after all this time?
みこさんに巫女として、いやエリート巫女アイドルとして…
Miko-san, as a shrine maiden—no, as an elite shrine maiden idol...
私からある提案というか使命を、言い返しに来たんです。
I've come to tell you of a proposal, or rather, a mission.
それは…よりパワーアップしたエリート巫女アイドルの姿になることです！
That is... to take on the form of an even more powered-up elite shrine maiden idol!
それから、みこは神と一緒に、よりパワーアップする為努力をした。
After that, Miko worked hard with the god to power up even further.
神はさくら神社の繁栄の為、みこはもっと、憧れのエリートなアイドルになるため。
The god for the prosperity of Sakura Shrine, and Miko to become an admired elite idol.
みこがよりアイドルで活躍して知名度をあげれば桜神社の廃れることはない…（建前）
If Miko raises her profile, Sakura Shrine won't go out of business... (Public stance)
そして…月日は流れ、今日
And so... time passed, and today,
さらなるエリートへ みこはなる！
Miko becomes an even greater elite!
昨日のセカンドフェスで、十分にアイドルパワーも溜まった。
In yesterday's 2nd Fest, I gathered plenty of idol power.
絶対に成功してやるで！
I'm definitely going to make this succeed!
みんな！見ててね！みこの新しい姿！
Everyone! Watch me! Miko's new form!
エリートみこの力、見せたれ！
I'll show you the power of elite Miko!
おーーーっ！
Ooh!
同じ未来を見たい あの夢手にしたい
Let's see the same future, let's make that dream ours.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go!
Running with our respective hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えていた
Sprouting in a pitch-black place no matter where we looked.
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
Our eyes were stolen by just a tiny glimmer of hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning our trembling hearts with anxiety smoothly.
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
Gathering just a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up" and moving forward.
苦しいときももう私はひとりじゃないから
Because even in tough times, I'm no longer alone.
だからもっと夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
So I want to chase my dreams more, my excitement won't stop.
想像越えてくる世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination.
アクセスしてみたい後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to try accessing it, I won't let you have any regrets.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go!
Running with our respective hearts, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky.
見たことのない光現実にとどくよ
Reach reality as an unseen light.
いつも聞こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers we always hear right here.
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
Making us want to search for a new light once again.
同じ 未来を 見ていたい
Wanting to see the same future
あの 夢 手に したい
Wanting to get that dream in hand
それぞれ 違っ た こころ で 走れ go ！
Running with different hearts, go!
どこ を 見 て も 真っ暗 な 場所 に 芽生え て い た
No matter where I looked, in the pitch-dark place where it sprouted
ほんの 小さな 希望 に この 瞳 奪わ れ た
My eyes were stolen by a tiny hope
不安 で 揺れる 心 を 上手 に チューニング し て
Tuning the heart shaking with anxiety well
ほんの 小さな 勇気 を 振り絞っ て い た
I was squeezing out a tiny bit of courage
諦め の 文字 デリート し て 進む
Deleting the word give up and moving forward
苦しい とき も もう 私 は ひとり じゃ ない から
Even when it's painful, I'm no longer alone anymore
だから もっと 夢 追いかけ たい
So I want to chase my dreams more
ワクワク 止まら ない
Excitement doesn't stop
想像 超え て くる 世界 見せ て あげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination
アクセス し て み たい 後悔 なんて させ ない
Wanting to access it, I won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ 違っ た こころ で 彩れ
Adorning with different hearts
仮想 の 空 に 輝く 眩しい 想い は
The dazzling thoughts shining in the virtual sky
見た こと の ない 光 を 現実 に 届ける よ
Deliver the light you've never seen before to reality
いつも 聴こえる エール は ここ に キャプチャー し て
Always capturing the cheers heard here
また 新しい 光 を 探し たく なる よ
I come to want to search for new light again
君 の 笑顔 は 保存 し て 進む
Saving your smile and moving forward
悲しい とき に 見返す よ
Looking back when I'm sad
力 が 湧く から 胸 を 張っ て 夢 追いかけ たい
Power wells up, so I want to stand proud and chase my dreams
奇跡 の 物語 （ ストーリー ） 一緒 に 作ろ う
Let's make a miraculous story together
終わら ない 夢 を
An endless dream
誰 一人 欠かす こと ない 愛 が 舞っ た この 世界
No one can be missed, this world where love danced
それぞれ 違っ た こころ で 彩る ね
Adorning with different hearts
悲しい とき も 寂しい とき も
Even when sad, even when lonely
信じ 合える もの が ある 忘れ ず に この 鼓動 鳴らし 続け たい
There is something we can believe in together, wanting to keep ringing this heartbeat without forgetting
終わら ない 世界 に 溢れ出す 笑顔 達
Smiles overflowing into an endless world
憧れ の 舞台 立ち たい 私 らしく 輝き たい
Wanting to stand on the stage of longing, wanting to shine like myself
とき に は 涙 し て また 笑い 合い たい
Sometimes shedding tears and wanting to smile together again
同じ 未来 を 見 たい あの 夢 手 に し たい
Wanting to see the same future, wanting to get that dream in hand
踏み出そ う 奇跡 の 一歩 を
Taking a miraculous first step
息切らし て 夢 追いかけ たい ワクワク 止まら ない
Out of breath, wanting to chase dreams, excitement doesn't stop
想像 超え て くる 世界 見せ て あげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination
アクセス し て み たい 後悔 なんて ない
Wanting to try accessing it, there's no regret here
夢 追いかけ たい
Wanting to chase dreams
ワクワク 止まら ない
Excitement doesn't stop
想像 超え て くる 世界 見せ て あげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination
アクセス し て み たい 後悔 なんて ない
Wanting to try accessing it, there's no regret here
それぞれ 違っ た こころ で つくる world
A world created with different hearts
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんなー！にゃっはろー！
Everyone! Nyahallo!
エリート巫女、スーパー・ベリベリ・元気カワ・アイドルな、さくらみこです！
Elite Miko, super, very, energetic, cute idol, Sakura Miko!
にこでーす！イエーイ！
Miko-desu! Yay!
カメラが気になって、カメラが気になってなんかうづうづしてしまった。にゃっはろー、みんな！
The camera made me so curious and fidgety. Nyahallo, everyone!
どう？みこの新しい 姿、どうですか？
How is it? What do you think of Miko's new appearance?
寄って寄って寄って！カメラ寄って寄って！
Come closer, come closer! Camera, come closer!
え、どうどう？みてみて！どう？かわいい？かわいい？イエーイ！
Um, how is it? Look, look! How is it? Cute? Cute? Yay!
やったー！あははは！ありがとー！
Yay! Ahahaha! Thank you!
はい、ということでね、「でこぼこでこぼこ」のね、「Shiny Smily Story」でしたー！
Yes, so that was the bumpy \"Shiny Smily Story\"!
ありがとー！どう？え、もうなんか...
Thank you! How is it? Um, like...
わあ！
Woah!
みて、みこのパンツさ、ちょっとね、後で、後であれなんだけど、封印されたで！
Look, Miko's pants, um, later, later, but they got sealed!
でもね、衣装はね、封印されなかった！やったー！
But the outfit wasn't sealed! Yay!
かわいい、あ、やった、ありがとー！はい！
Cute, oh yay, thank you! Yes!
ということで、今日は...
So, today...
みこのね、新3Dお披露目に来てくれて、みんな、本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming to Miko's new 3D debut!
えっとね、初のね、さくらみこ新3Dお披露目で、たくさん...
Um, for Miko's first new 3D debut, a lot...
呟いてください！そして、ま、ゲスト、とか？
Please tweet! And, well, guests, or?
ゲストとか、あとは... ま、嬉しいお知らせとかね、たくさんありますから！
Guests, or... well, happy announcements and stuff, there are a lot!
最後まで絶対に逃がすんじゃねえぞ！最後まで見抜んだぞ、みこの顔見て満足すんじゃねえぞ！
Definitely don't let it go until the very end! Watch till the very end, don't just be satisfied looking at Miko's face!
はい、ということで、それではね、そろそろ...
Yes, so, well, now...
なんか、みこのところで待ってるやつがいるらしいからね。
It seems there's someone waiting for me over at Miko's place.
ちょっとね、ま、移動しますか。ね！それではー！
So, um, shall we move? Yeah! Well then!
あれ？
Huh?
みこ先輩遅いぺこだけど、
Miko-senpai is late, peko, but
どこにいるぺこなんだ？
where could she be, peko?
うしろだ！
Behind you!
ここだよ！
Here!
うしろだよ！
Behind you!
ここ？
Here?
うしろだよ！
Behind you!
ここだよ！
Here!
それは違うだろ！
That's wrong!
これ違げえの！
This is wrong!
あれ、もしかして…
Wait, could it be...
違げえだろ、こっちだろ！
That's wrong, it's over here!
え、こんな神棚の中に、なんか入ってるね、ぺこなの？
Eh, is someone inside this kamidana, peko?
違げえだろ、こっちだろ！
That's wrong, it's this way!
やーい！
Yay!
あれ？ あとなんか…
Huh? Also...
あ！
Ah!
あれ？
Huh?
どう？ どう？ どう？
How is it? How is it? How is it?
なんだか変わったと…
It somehow changed...
みこ先輩、久しぶり！ぺこちゃんだ！
Miko-senpai, long time no see! It's Pekora, peko!
え？ なにそれ、それじゃ。
Huh? What's that, then?
あれ？
Huh?
なんか、なにか変わったと思わないか？ おい！
Don't you think something changed? Hey!
違げえだろ！
That's wrong!
久しぶりぺこじゃん！
Long time no see, peko!
え、みこ先輩、なんか、めちぇめちぇ、幼くなった？ぺこ？
Eh, Miko-senpai, did you somehow get super-duper younger, peko?
え？ そう、みこ的には、ちょっと…
Eh? Well, Miko-wise, I'm a bit...
まあ、成長したかなって思うんですけど。
thinking I've grown up a bit, though.
どこが？
Where?
ロリコン増した？ え、ほんと？
Did you get more lolicon? Eh, really?
めちゃめちゃなんかロリコンもしてるしさ、いい感じぺこよね？
You're totally acting like a lolicon too, isn't it a good vibe, peko?
そうでしょ？ なんかさらにポンコツ感が…
That's right, right? It feels like your uselessness has even...
なにが？ なんかポンコツ感が増してる感じがするぺこ？
What? Does it feel like your uselessness has increased, peko?
違げえだろ！
That's wrong!
なんか変にキュートになったのどう考えても。え、全身ちょっと見てみてもいいここ？
How on earth did you get weirdly cute? Eh, can I take a look at your whole body?
あ、どうぞ、撮ってください。
Ah, go ahead, take a picture.
あ、気づきました？ おい、ちょっと待てぺこで、え
Ah, did you notice? Hey, wait a second, peko, eh
許せないよな、このライブ。見てよ、この、このケープ。え、でも、やばいしょ、これ。え、でも、これペコじゃねえの、冬でさ。
Unforgivable, this live performance. Look at this cape. Eh, but, isn't this crazy? Eh, but, isn't this Peko, in winter?
あの、ケイトのパンツいい感じになって、お腹冷えないようにぺこじゃないの？
Um, the Kate pants are in good shape, so it's not so your stomach doesn't get cold, peko?
まあそれはそうなんだけどね、でもね、これ穿かないとね、ダメって言われちゃったんだよ、とうとう。
Well, that's true, but you know, if I don't wear these, they told me it's no good, finally.
まあ、ちょっと、なかなかなセンシティブな衣装でもあるぺこもんね。
Well, it's a pretty sensitive outfit too, peko.
お願い、ちっちゃい子みたいのもんじゃん！頑張って作ったのに。
Please, you look like a little kid! Even though I worked hard to make it.
でも、ケイトのパンツもかわいい、似合ってるぺこだよ。よかったぺこね。
But Kate's pants are also cute, it suits you, peko. Good for you, peko.
チョロいぺこだな。ありがとよ。
You're easily swayed, peko. Thanks.
いや、今日ぺこらさん、みこ先輩の家に来たぺこだけど。
Well, today Pekora-san came over to Miko-senpai's house, peko.
そう！ だってさ、だってさ
That's right! Because, because
なんか呼ばれたぺこだけど、なんか、あれなの？ やっぱみこさ、この、この可愛い姿をさ、
I was called over, peko, but like, what is it? After all, Miko, you want to show off this cute appearance,
嘘だに一番に自慢したいじゃん！
You want to brag to Usada first of all!
やっぱ、やっぱぺこらのこと好きすぎるぺこなの？
After all, do you love Pekora too much, peko?
違うんだろって！
That's wrong!
マウントだよ、マウント。みこも可愛いこだぞ。ぺこらのことそんなに好きじゃなくて
It's a flex, a flex. Miko is a cute child too. It's not like I like Pekora that much,
ていうか、ライバルに、ライバル？
I mean, rivals? Rivals?
はあ、じゃないでしょ。で、今日は撮影とか手伝ってもらったり、
Ha, that's not it. So today you can help with filming and stuff,
あと、あのゲームやろうぜ、あのゲーム。去年やったやつ、去年？
And, let's play that game, that game. The one we did last year, last year?
やったじゃん！APEになってじゃん！こうやって、あ、あの
We did it! We became APEX! Like this, ah, that
あれぺこな？ そう、赤とか黄色とか緑とかあるやつぺこでしょ？
What is it, peko? Right, the one with red, yellow, green, etc., peko?
あ、APEXやろう、やろうぺこだよ！あんたね！
Ah, let's play APEX, let's do it, peko! You!
え、これぺこらがさ、指示していいやつぺこ？
Eh, is this one where Pekora gives instructions, peko?
まあね、なんか本当はそんな予定じゃなかったんだけどね。あ、本当？ 色んな都合上ね。
Well, you know, actually it wasn't really scheduled like that. Ah, really? Due to various circumstances.
あ、なんか、なんかイケニエにできなくなったっていう（笑） だからね、その仕方ないと思う。
Ah, like, I couldn't make you a sacrifice anymore (laughs) So, I think it couldn't be helped.
え、待ってじゃさ、ぺこらのちょっとお勧めのあれやってもいいですか？
Eh, wait then, can I do some of Pekora's recommended stuff?
なんかポーズある？ あったら四つんばいになってまず。え？
Is there a pose? If there is, get on all fours first. Eh?
お前さ、その平壁なんだの？ お前、毎回ほろめにあてるじゃん！
Hey, what's with that wall? Hey, you always put me through hell!
あれでぺこらこ、あ、ぺこらどこにしようかな、ここにするか？ どうぞ。
As for Pekora, ah, where should I put Pekora, here? Go ahead.
あ、いいね。こっち向きなさい、ぺこ。あ、いで、にゃんちゃんのポーズ撮ってにゃんでしょ？
Ah, nice. Face this way, peko. Ah, wait, you want me to do the kitty pose, right?
またにゃんだよ、これ。こっちの方がいいかもぺこら。あ、い、いいね！
Again with the 'nyan', this. This might be better, Pekora. Ah, y-yeah, nice!
これさ、去年もやったでしょ、これ。なんか言ってよ、セリフ。
We did this last year too, right? Say something, a line.
にゃんにゃん！あ、可愛いぺこだな、にゃん！ お金だ、お金。
Nyan-nyan! Ah, cute, peko, nyan! Money, money.
え、なんかめちゃめちゃぺこら… 可愛いぺこだな、おい！
Eh, Pekora is somehow super... cute, peko, hey!
うわ、水着いい感じぺこだよ、おい！
Whoa, the swimsuit is a nice vibe, peko, hey!
じゃさ、ちょっとさ、振り返りもやって、振り返り。
So, hey, let's also do a look-back, look-back.
ああ、それもなんか、もうやったね。パンツが見えちゃうじゃん！
Ah, we already did that too. Your panties are showing!
うれし、ぺこで、じゃあ、ぺこらがみこ先輩つったら振り返ってね。オッケー！
I'm happy, peko, so when Pekora says Miko-senpai, turn around, okay? Okay!
みこ先輩ーい！
Miko-senpai!
なんでパンチでよんないの？ そこ、パンチで言うとこじゃん！なんだよ！
Why didn't you punch? That's the place to punch! What is this!
なんで同じ人じゃないの？ じゃ行くよ。
Why isn't it the same person? Okay, here we go.
はい、パンチ！
Yes, punch!
なつかし！ それやりたいだけぺこでしょ、あんた。面白いなこれ。
Nostalgic! You just wanted to do that, didn't you. This is funny.
明らかに、ちょっと後ろも見ていい？ 後ろ？ セクシーだね。
Obviously, can I look at the back too? The back? It's sexy.
自分のさ、そんな変わってないでしょ？ ちょっと背中見せて、ぺこだよ。背中。
Your own hasn't changed that much, right? Show me your back, peko. Your back.
あの背中もチラチラとした感じの、あ、や、この背中、背負ってるもんがあるでしょ？
That back with a flickering feeling, ah, yeah, this back, you've got things you're carrying, right?
ひたすらしょ、背負ってるぺこだね、色々と。
You're just carrying things on your back, peko, various things.
どうなんだろ？ でもやっぱり表情いろいろ見たいな。100面相やってくれてね、ぺこ。
How is it? But still, I want to see various facial expressions. Do a hundred expressions, peko.
なんか なんだ… なんか今のなかなか見ないビジュアルでしょ？
That was a pretty rare visual, wasn't it?
なんか褒めて 褒めて
Praise me, praise me!
そうだな…
I suppose...
なんかセクシー路線でいけばいいじゃん。
Why don't you go with a sexy route?
まぁ、いつもがセクシーみたいなもんですから
Well, since everyday is pretty much sexy...
はっ、どうぞ！
Hah, go ahead!
なんか色々ここからでしょ、ほら。
There's various things from here, look.
あ、いいぺこだね。ダッチュのやつ？
Ah, that's good peko. The 'Datchu' pose?
ダッチュのやつ。
The 'Datchu' pose.
どう？
How is it?
うん、なんか違うな。
Hmm, somehow it's different.
なんか違うくね？ペコラ。あ、その顔めっちょええペコじゃん。
Doesn't it look different, Peko? Ah, that face is really good peko.
エリートです。
I am an elite.
あ、いいね。
Ah, that's nice.
どうや？
How's that?
あ、かわいい かわいい。ペコだよ。
Ah, cute cute. It's peko.
え、嘘？これでかっこいい決まってる？
Eh, really? Does this look cool and determined?
決まってる。なんか銃ぶっぱなしてそう。
Determined. Looks like you're about to fire a gun.
ぶわーー！やったやった！
Bwaaa! I did it, I did it!
じゃあ、うつぶせして、うつぶせ。
Then, lie face down, face down.
うつぶせってなんだっけ？天井だっけ？そうそう天井向いてペコ。
What was face down again? The ceiling? That's right, face the ceiling, peko.
あ、でも疲れたから…
Ah, but I'm tired so...
じゃあ1回休もうか。
Then let's take a break for a bit.
そっち、そっちでやろう。そっちでやろう。
Let's do it on that side, on that side.
いや、ちょっと、はい。うつぶせしてくれペコ。
No, wait, yes. Lie face down, peko.
なんで？
Why?
いいから。
Never mind.
可愛いよ。落とせないから。
You're cute. Because I won't drop it.
大丈夫ペコ？
Are you okay, peko?
やめなさいよ！
Cut it out!
またパンツ見せてくんじゃないのあんた。
You're gonna show your panties again, aren't you?
見せないもん。
I won't show them.
おーー！ぴこぴきが。
Ooh! The piko-piki is...
あ、いい。
Ah, nice.
あ、いいね。なんか… なんかちょっとそそら… あ、寝てんのあんた？
Ah, nice. Somehow... it's kind of alluring... Ah, are you sleeping?
寝ない寝ない、はい。配信中ペコだよ！配信中起きな！
I'm not sleeping, yes. I'm streaming, peko! Wake up while streaming!
いや楽しいな、久しぶりに。
Man, it's fun, for the first time in a while.
ね、なんか久しぶりにMiko先輩ペコちゃんね、来た気がするペコ。
Right? It feels like it's been a while since Miko-senpai and Pekora-chan came together, peko.
すげえな。
Amazing.
なんかポーズペコ？
Some pose, peko?
本当そんなに。
Really, not that much.
変わった、でも変わったでも… てか嘘だのポーズあるよ。
Different, but different, but... wait, there's Usada's pose.
どれ？ねぇ馬鹿にしてんのあんた！
Which one? Hey, are you making fun of me?
あと馬鹿にしてたりさ、ねえねえやってよさー、なんか。やってないよ！やってないペコでしょ！
And making fun of me, hey, do it, do something. I'm not doing it! You're doing it, peko!
こんなやつ。ねえあんた馬鹿にしすぎじゃない？
This kind of guy. Hey, aren't you making fun of me too much?
いや、ペコがいつも作った、ねえ、MMDのさ、写真？
No, the MMD photo that Peko always makes, hey?
あ、作ってんだあいつ。あげてる。土下座のやつ。
Ah, that guy makes them. Uploading them. The dogeza one.
ペコラび、みこ先輩のさ、ペコラの作ったMMDで1番好きなのは土下座ペコなんだけど。
Pekora's, Miko-senpai's, my favorite MMD made by Pekora is the dogeza peko.
あれめっちゃかわいいでしょ？また土下座させてあげるね。あ、めっちゃ…ちょっとお願いよ、せーの！
Isn't that super cute? I'll let you dogeza again. Ah, super... hey, please, ready, go!
なんか嫌なんだけど。早く。5、4… なんだよ、なんでそんな悪くしなきゃいけないのに。1、すいません。
I don't really want to. Hurry. 5, 4... What's this, why do I have to make it look so bad. 1, I'm sorry.
スクショして、スクショして、スクショを今のダイブペコだからね。謝る時とかの時…
Take a screenshot, take a screenshot, screenshot this dive peko. When apologizing or...
やってないのになんでみこ使っていいペコだから！使っていいの？土下座させられた。
Even though I didn't do it, why can Miko use it, peko! Can I use it? I was made to dogeza.
あ、いいじゃんみんなかわいいって言ってくれてるペコでしょ。
Ah, it's fine, everyone is saying it's cute, peko.
嘘でしょ、くさって言ってるぞ。
No way, they're saying it stinks.
ちょっと見なよ、おい。
Look at that, hey.
あ、なんかいろんなものにされてる今日。エリートのアイドルの姿見せると言いつつに。
Ah, I'm being turned into various things today. While saying I'll show an elite idol's appearance...
たくさんね、使ってくだされペコな。なんかそういうのいいね、なんか使えそうな動き。ポーズねの。使えそうなやつ、使えるそうなやつ？あ、さっきのごめんねやったじゃん。
Use it a lot, peko. Something like that is nice, like usable movements. Poses, right. Usable things, usable things? Ah, you did the 'sorry' one earlier.
ごめんねやったじゃん。
You did the 'sorry' one.
おはよう、せーの！
Good morning, ready, go!
にす…
Nisu...
ね、やめて。やめて。
Hey, stop it. Stop it.
あ、下からさ、みこピーたちがさ、みこ先輩がさ、おはようって、それぐるぐる。
Ah, from below, Miko-p's, Miko-senpai, saying good morning, spinning around.
おはよう。おはよう。おやすみ。おやすみ、せーの！
Good morning. Good morning. Good night. Good night, ready, go!
おやすみ。にあ、かわいい。
Good night. Nya, cute.
あ、それめっちゃいいペコだね。
Ah, that's a super good peko.
これ欲しいね。かしゃ。
I want this. Snap.
かしゃ。あ、いいね。たくさん撮れそうじゃん。
Snap. Ah, nice. Seems like we can take a lot.
あとなんだろう？なんかある？ここポイント。
What else? Is there anything? Here's a point.
よし、解読だ。船長の…
Alright, deciphering. The Captain's...
はい、方丈マリンです。
Yes, it's Houshou Marine.
方丈マリンですー。
It's Houshou Marine.
パクりすぎだペコでしょ。
You're ripping her off too much, peko.
え、みこ先輩のそれないの？
Eh, doesn't Miko-senpai have that?
え、みこなの？あるよ。貧乏神の神。
Eh, Miko's? I have it. The god of poverty.
貧乏神だよ！に、神社のさ、スーパーエリートみこ、神社ー！
The god of poverty! Ni, the shrine's super elite Miko, shrine!
ちょっとさい… ちょっとダサいペコよそれ。
A little sa... that's a bit uncool, peko.
ちょっとあまりにもなんか長からじゃん。
It's a little too long.
あ、そういうことね。じゃあ今度考えておいてペコだよ。今度やる時ね。
Ah, I see. Then think about it next time, peko. Next time you do it.
いや、いいね。なんか、めちゃんこ可愛い子の音ペコぞの。
Well, it's nice. Like, super cute girl sound, peko.
本当？
Really?
うん、なんか、もう馬鹿にできないね、みこになって。
Yeah, like, you can't make fun of Miko anymore.
よりポンコツになった？
Did you become even more ponkotsu?
あ、ほじっちゃった？
Ah, did you pick your nose?
ほじってない、ほじってない。なんかあんた耳遠くなって、よりポンコツになった感じがすごいするペコ。
I didn't pick, I didn't pick. You feel even more ponkotsu because your ears got bad.
でもかわいいよ、めちゃめちゃ。みんなもほじってるんじゃねペコなみんなのコメントなんだから。
But it's cute, super cute. Everyone's picking too, peko, since these are everyone's comments.
きゃーって言ってる。きゃーって。
Saying 'Kyaa!'. Saying 'Kyaa!'.
キラキラしてるペコだって。ガチ恋してるってさ。じゃあね、ちょっとガチ恋距離さ移っちゃおうかなってやつ。
Sparkling, peko. They say they're in gachikoi. Well then, maybe I'll move into the gachikoi distance.
画面近づいてキスだ。いや、ないよそんなの。
Approaching the screen for a kiss. No, there's no such thing.
あるペコでしょ。ないないない、本当ない。
There is, peko. No, no, no, really no.
ちょっと、ほら、しめてよ。ちょっとやればいいでしょ。
Hold on, look, wrap it up. Just do it.
やめるんだペコ！ やめるんだペコ！
Stop it, peko! Stop it, peko!
あ、そっか、ほうれん草に人参持って...持ってたんだもん！
Ah, right, holding spinach and carrots... I was holding them!
ビックリしたペコ！
You gave me a scare, peko!
にんじんになっ…あ、まって、にんじんになってしまったで！これ！
It turned into a car— wait, it turned into a carrot, this!
印刷されてるペコじゃん、にんじんに！だから、にんじんになってしまったで、これ！
It's printed as a carrot, peko! So it turned into a carrot, this!
あ、そっか今度からね、ずっとそれを使ってやってもらうペコだからね！
Ah, right, from now on, you're gonna use that all the time to do it, peko!
しかもなんか方向が微妙で武器にならない！ 内側にいってるペコだからね！
Also the direction is subtle and it's not a weapon! It's going inwards, peko!
あ、いうことペコな。あ、用意してもらったんだね、用意。
Ah, I see, peko. Ah, you prepared it, right? Preparation.
何？どれどれ？出たよ！みこのやつ、どん！え？出るかな？
What? Let's see! It's out! Miko's one, bam! Eh? Will it come out?
なんか出るペコなの？出るはず。
Is it gonna come out, peko? It should come out.
ね、と、あれ？なっつかしいペコだね！これ、これ、これ！
Hey, and, oh? So nostalgic, peko! This, this, this!
嘘のやんな？え、やだなぁ！
You're lying, right? Eh, no way!
リアルペコだよ！やんな、これ！
It's real peko! Do it, this!
めちゃめちゃそれ大変なやつやん、去年ペコらとさ、死んだやつじゃんことさ！
That's super tough, last year with Pekora, we died on this, right?!
えー、なんでここでまた再開したかっていうと、やっぱ国生みアスが近いからってわけやな。
Uh, why did we restart this here? Because Kuniumi As is close, that's why.
え、ペコら今回指示していいってこと？
Eh, Pekora, can I give instructions this time?
え？ペコらがず、え、ことペコですか？みこ先輩！
Eh? Pekora's zu, eh, what peko? Miko-senpai!
はーい、うっきうきチャンネルか。じゃあペコら、ルーレットスタート！
Hiii, Ukki-uki channel. Then Pekora, roulette start!
どぅるるるるるるるるる…ペコちゃんパンツ見えても大丈夫やからね！
Dururururu... Pekora, it's okay even if your panties show!
あ、オッケーペコ、じゃあ際どい感じでもいいってことか？そんなことはない。
Ah, okay peko, so even a risqué feeling is fine? Not really.
そうではない。あ、そうではない。うん。
Not like that. Ah, not like that. Yeah.
右足が、きみどり！右足が…
Right foot, yellow-green! Right foot is...
最初はね簡単ペコだよね！よよよよよ！
At first it's easy peko, right! Yayaya!
あ、でもなんか…で、まずはなん個あるペコ？
Ah, but like... and first, how many are there, peko?
そしたらペコラスル、ルーレット！うん、角！ぴーん！はい！
Then Pekora's Ru, roulette! Yeah, corner! Ping! Yes!
左手が、左手が…ん？左手？赤！左手が赤！
Left hand, left hand... hm? Left hand? Red! Left hand is red!
あ、まだ楽勝ペコか。2個目だもん。あれ、ちょっときつそう。
Ah, still an easy win, peko. It's the second one. Oh, looks a bit tough.
全然余裕。あ、ね、あ、さすがエリートペコだからね、そこはね！全然余裕ペコだよね！
Totally fine. Ah, hey, ah, as expected of an elite peko, so there! Totally easy peko, right!
じゃ、ペコラールーレット、スタート！
Now, Pekora's roulette, start!
ちゃん、ちゃん！左足、え？青！
Chan, chan! Left foot, eh? Blue!
左足、あと奥めで、奥の方ね、奥の方ね。あう！あう！
Left foot, and further back, towards the back, towards the back. Ow! Ow!
あー！おペコだって！アホペコだって！
Ahh! An honorable peko! A foolish peko!
いや、アイドルとして大！変！なことになって…
No, as an idol, it's a HUGE deal...
膝立ててだめペコだよ、膝。右足の膝。
You can't put your knees down, knees. The right leg's knee.
あー！そうそうそうそう！それなら大丈夫だ！
Ahh! That's right, that's right! Then it's fine!
そしたら、ペコラールーレット、スタート！
Then, Pekora's roulette, start!
右手！右手、はい！赤！赤！
Right hand! Right hand, yes! Red! Red!
あ、いいペコだん…あ、待って、今最高にまぬけなかっ、かっこしてるよ。
Ah, good peko... ah, wait, right now I'm in the most dorky, ridiculous pose.
まだ、いて！
Still, ouch!
バカ！おれ！いて！めちゃめちゃつらいんだからね！真剣なんだからね！
Idiot! Me! Ouch! It's super tough, you know! I'm serious, you know!
じゃあ、ペコラールーレット、スタート！だめだ。
Then, Pekora's roulette, start! No good.
ちょっと楽な体勢にしようペコか。うん。えっと、右足、はい！黄色！
Let's make it a slightly easier pose, peko. Yeah. Um, right foot, yes! Yellow!
あ、いいじゃん！あ、ちょっと楽になったね。
Ah, nice! Ah, it got a bit easier.
ペコラールーレット、スタート！ちゃん！左足、緑！
Pekora's roulette, start! Chan! Left foot, green!
あ、ずれそうになるか、そうなるっちまうペコか。
Ah, about to slip, or it ends up like that, peko.
あ、逃げたね！あ、逃げたね！こんな大体になるとは思わなかった。くそ！うれしいな！
Ah, you ran away! Ah, you ran away! I didn't think it would come to this kind of big deal. Damn! I'm happy!
じゃあペコラールーレット、スタート！ちゃん！
Then Pekora's roulette, start! Chan!
左手、緑！左手どうしよっ、こっち！こっちを！緑！
Left hand, green! Left hand, what should I do, this way! This way! Green!
緑同士か。うれしいだよ！もうやだ！いけるいける！
Green to green. I'm happy! No more! I can do it, I can do it!
緑同士かないよ！
Green to green isn't possible!
え、エリートみこがここで終了ということペコか？これ広すぎるで、これ！
Eh, elite Miko is finishing right here, peko? This is too wide, this!
ひどくに、ペコいけるペコでしょ！うれしいだよ！わら！
Terribly, peko can do it, peko! I'm happy! Lol!
拷問かなってきているペコだけど。あ、寝ちゃったよ！
Feels like torture, peko. Ah, she fell asleep!
いや、あんたエリートとしてもっと頑張んなきゃペコだよ！
No, as an elite, you gotta try harder, peko!
いや、本当に去年よりも全然できない。去年もできなかったけど今年もできねぇな。
No, really, I can't do it at all compared to last year. I couldn't last year either, but I can't this year either.
来年はきっとうまくいくペコだよ。絶対やらすからね、みこもキツネツスターゲーム。
Next year will surely go well, peko. I'll definitely make you do it, Miko, the Kitsune Twister game.
なんでよ！ペコらは、見てるほうが楽しかった。ルーレットやってるほうがすごい楽しかったペコ。
Why! Pekora, watching was more fun. Doing the roulette was way more fun, peko.
人が殺し合ってる姿
People killing each other...
そうやって楽しみにしてやって、おもしろ遊びこですごい。
enjoying it like that, it's such fun play.
ま、ね、次からはね、うさのあかはね
Well, next time, Usada's...
あ、絶対3Dやったら呼んだよねみこのこと。
Oh, if it's 3D, you'd definitely invite Miko.
あ、オッケーぺこで。
Ah, okay peko.
ツイッターで呼んでよ。
Invite me on Twitter.
やったらぺこね、ツイッターで呼ぶことになったらまこ先輩呼ぶぺこだけど、たぶんね。
If it comes down to Twitter, I'll invite Miko-senpai, probably.
聞く前からね。
Even before asking.
でもね、うん。
But yeah, um.
今日は、何？みんなにお知らせがあるんだよね。
Today, what? We have an announcement for everyone.
え？ YouTubeぺこなの？
Eh? YouTube peko?
言うちゃよ。
Just say it.
言うちゃの？
Say it?
言うちゃよ。
Just say it.
え、秘密でもいいぺこなの？せーので言ってください。
Eh, even if it's a secret? Let's say it on three.
あ、せーので？
Ah, on three?
え、これ？うんうん？
Eh, this? Um, um?
これ？そうそうそうそうそう。
This? That's right, exactly.
あ、けけけ。
Ah, okay.
行くよ？
Ready?
せーの！ぺこみこ…
Ready, go! PekoMiko...
ぺこみこ クリスマスお泊り会！
PekoMiko Christmas Sleepover!
ぺこみこ クリスマスお泊り会 イェーイ！
PekoMiko Christmas Sleepover, Yay!
え、これいつやるぺこなの？でもみこ先輩。
Eh, when is this, peko? But Miko-senpai.
今日の…今日の20、20、30、3…
Today's... today at 20, 20, 30, 3...
23の…半？11時半からぺこみこのクリスマスお泊り会をやたいと思いますぺこ！イェーイ！
from 11:30, we're holding the PekoMiko Christmas sleepover! Yay!
チャンネルぺこ。
Peko channel.
あれ、去年以来ってことだね？
Huh, it's been since last year, right?
ね。
Yeah.
え、去年もやりかやってたよね？
Eh, we did it last year too, right?
お泊まりゆうてもさ、今回はね、みこの家だからね。
As for a sleepover, this time it's at Miko's house.
あ、そうそう、みこ先輩のお家で、お酒とかね飲んだりとかねしながら楽しくパーティしたいなっていう感じで。
Ah, right, at Miko-senpai's house, drinking alcohol and having a fun party.
そうだね、ゆるゆるっとクリスマスみんなでもらおうね！
That's right, let's all have a cozy Christmas together!
そう、ぺこなよ！
Yeah, peko!
やったね！
Awesome!
え、家片つけた？
Eh, did you tidy up your house?
うん、片付けたよ！
Yeah, I tidied it up!
うん、片付けたよ、急いでね。
Yeah, I tidied it up in a hurry.
やった、うん、期待するぺこだからね。
Yay, well, I'm counting on you, peko.
やめて、あさ、あさんないでね、マジで。
Stop, don't go snooping around, seriously.
なんかちょっと変なエロゲとかがポンポンで出てたらちょっと、ま、それは置いとるけど。
Some weird eroge or something pops out, well, I'll leave that alone.
置いとるんかい！
You are leaving it there!
ぜひね、見に来てくださいねと。
Please come and watch us, everyone.
ということで、一瞬のうさのままたんバイバイだけどね。
So, it's a brief goodbye for Usada Mamatain, though.
そうだね、ありがとね、頑張ってぺこね。
That's right, thanks, do your best peko.
うん、この後も頑張るんで、ありがと！
Yeah, I'll keep doing my best, thanks!
バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
ちゅうことてね、まあぺこみこクリスマスはないかと思ったが、あります！イェーイやったぜ！
So, I thought there wouldn't be a PekoMiko Christmas, but there is! Yay, awesome!
ということでね、け、うんうんうんもね、呼んでるからね。
So, we're inviting... uh, everyone.
ぺこぱしーの、おやつのじきもあるからね、ま、くっちゃくっちゃしたいと思います。
With Peko-chan, we'll have snack time, so we want to chat and munch away.
よろしくお願いします！ということで！
Thank you very much! So...
そろそろ、行ていうかな、みこ準備してた
It's almost time to go, Miko has prepared...
ものがあるで、まだまだ続きますからね！楽しみにしててくださいね！よろしくお願いします！ということで！
things, so it's going to continue! Please look forward to it! Thank you!
さて、ここからはだだだだだん！やるげ、ヒロインチャレンジのコーナー！
Now, from here on, boom! It's the Heroine Challenge corner!
まあね、より可愛くなったみこちゃんですからね！
Well, Miko-chan has gotten even cuter, you see!
え、今からですね、みこと色々なシチュエーションを、え、やってもらいました。
So, starting now, Miko will be in various situations.
で、お話の進行、まあ、これ選択肢があるんですけど、分岐ルートね。
And for the story progression, well, there are choices, branching routes.
それは、あのコメントの多い順で選択肢されていくから、
Those will be chosen based on the most comments,
くれぐれも間違ったやつをやらないように！オケイ？メインも参加してね！
so please be careful not to pick the wrong one! Okay? Everyone participate too!
みんなが主人公ってわけですね！はい、ということで、それでは始まるね！
Everyone is the protagonist, right? Yes, so, it's about to begin!
【35P】ここは……どこだ？さっきまでみこちのお披露目配信を観てたのに、もしかして本当に・・ギャルゲがはじまったのか！？
[35P]: Where... where is this? I was just watching Miko's 3D debut stream... Could it be that a galge actually started!?
【みこ】あれ？みこぴ～？こんなところで何してんの？
[Miko]: Huh? Mikopi~? What are you doing in a place like this?
【35P】あ、れは・・昔のみこち！？
[35P]: Ah, is that... the old Miko!?
【みこ】昔？何言ってるの？それよりそれより、今悩んでることがあってさ、みこ方向性っていうのに・・悩んでるんだよね。
[Miko]: Old? What are you talking about? More importantly, I've got something on my mind... I'm worried about my... direction as an idol.
【みこ】ホロライブに入ったはいいものの、みこ本当にアイドルになれるのかな？芸人って言われるし・・もう諦めた方がいいのかなぁ？
[Miko]: It's great that I joined Hololive, but can I really become an idol? People call me a comedian... maybe I should just give up?
【35P】そうか・・ここは過去、みこの過去なのか。ギャルゲの中でも俺が導いてやりたいゾ…！
[35P]: I see... this is the past, Miko's past. Even in a galge, I want to guide her...!
【35P】みこちは――
[35P]: Miko is—
芸人だよ
A comedian.
アイドルだよ
An idol.
どう思う？
"What do you think?"
アイドル？
"An idol?"
芸人に？
"A comedian?"
アイドルだよ。誰がなんと言ったって、
みこちは俺のアイドルだ！
"An idol. No matter what anyone says,
Miko is my idol!"
あ、ありがとう。へへ、
みこも自信持てないとね！
"Ah, thank you. Hehe, Miko needs
to be more confident too!"
いつも励ましてくれて
ありがとね、みこぴー！
"Thank you for always
cheering me up, Mikopii!"
みこぴーはいい子だね！
よしよしよしよし……
"Mikopii is such a good boy!
There, there, there..."
（みこち・・・捕まってるやんけ・・・）
(Miko... you're getting arrested...)
うわああああん！みこは何悪くないでー！
ちょっと強盗やっただけで！
"Waaaaah! Miko didn't do anything wrong!
I just did a little robbery!"
自業自得、なんだよなぁ・・
"You brought this on yourself..."
もうすぐライブなのにこんなところにいたら
ステージに立てないよおお・・・釈放して欲しいな…
"The live is coming up soon, and I can't
make it to the stage... Please release me!"
うーん、かわいいから釈放♡！
"Hmm, you're cute, so you're released♡!"
ありがとうおお！みこ、がんばるね！
みこぴーは優しいな〜
"Thank you so much! Miko will do her best!
Mikopii, you're so kind~"
この、このっ！
"Take that, take that!"
みこぴーどあお？似合ってる？
みこのアイドル衣装だよ〜！
"Mikopii-do? Does it suit me?
It's Miko's idol outfit~!"
すごく似合ってる！かわいい！
さすがぽんこつエリートだな！
"It suits you so well! So cute!
Truly an elite clumsy idol!"
ほんこつは余計なんですけど！
でも・・・緊張しすぎて逃げたい・・・
"Clumsy is uncalled for! But...
I'm so nervous I want to run away..."
みこダンスも上手ないし、みこよりもっと
かわいいみんながいるのに・・・大丈夫かな？
"Miko's dancing isn't even that good... will they
cheer for me with light sticks? Will I be okay?"
弱音吐くんじゃねぇ！
思いっきり楽しんでおいで！
"Don't go whining!
Go out there and have a blast!"
いつも優しく背中押してくれてありがとうね。
それでもアイドルだって信じてくれてありがとう。
"Thank you for always supporting me. Even when
I'm clumsy, thank you for believing I'm an idol."
みこ、がんばるからずっとみこぴーでいてね！
それじゃ〜、ハイテンションでアイドルしてくるにぇ〜！
"Miko will do her best, so keep being my Mikopii!
Now then, I'm gonna go be a high-tension idol~!"
はーい！みんなー！エリートみこ、
アイドルの！さくらみこだよー！いぇい！
"Hi everyone! Elite Miko,
the idol! Sakura Miko! Yay!"
ということで、今日はみこのお披露目と、
あとはライブに来てくれてありがとう！
"So, thank you everyone for coming
to Miko's 3D reveal and live today!"
ということで、今日は・・・なんとなんと！
みんなに新曲がありまーす！いぇい！
"And so, today... guess what!
We have a brand new song for everyone! Yay!"
ということで、びっくりしてるよみんなのね、
びっくりした？はーい！
"So, everyone looks so surprised,
were you surprised? Yay!"
ということで、それではさっそく歌いたいと思います！
聞いてください！さくら色ハイテンション！
"With that, we'd like to perform it right away!
Please listen to it! 'Sakurairo High Tension'!"
ねぇこっち向いてほら瞳合わせてよ
そっと息を止めて
"Hey, look over here, meet my gaze,
and hold your breath for a moment"
重ね合わせたさくら色の
甘い息継ぎ止めてよね
"Stop that sweet,
cherry-blossom-colored breath we share"
実戦 今日も満喫中
Real battle, enjoying today too!
おの今いい敷いてね
Laying down a good vibe right now!
1分1秒待ったなし
Not a single second to wait,
全力楽しんだもん勝ち
Enjoying it fully is how you win!
オーイェイ！
Oh yeah!
レッツゴー ハブヤデッドキューハ イヌイチャエ ワンツースリー
Let's go! Have ya dead cue ha inu ichae 1, 2, 3!
恋のステップ 踏んで
Stepping to the rhythm of love,
十人十色の請求書
A custom bill for everyone's tastes,
Let's cook 5-7 vibes kissしてよ
Let's cook 5-7 vibes, kiss me!
スーパーハイテンション まだ足りない 祭はもっと夢中にさせて
Super high tension, still not enough! Make this festival even more exciting,
ウルトラハイテンション キミと見つめ合うまま
Ultra high tension, staring right into your eyes!
ラブユー ハイパーハイテンション 改めてね必勝の合図 乗りたいやめば
Love you! Hyper high tension, a winning signal renewed—if you want to ride it, stop!
ミラクルハイテンション キミと目指してキューピッド
Miracle high tension, aiming for you, Cupid!
ほら 弾けそうな胸の鼓動 受け止めてよネ
Look, receive the beating of my ready-to-burst heart!
全身全霊 充実中
Body and soul, fully fulfilled!
オーイェイ エリタ いいねいいね
Oh yeah, elita, nice nice!
うっかり 炎上しちゃったって
Oops, even if I accidentally start a fire,
全力楽しんだもん勝ち
Enjoying it fully is how you win!
ヘイヨン レッツゴー ハブヤデッドキューハ イヌイチャエ 水面わ
Hey on! Let's go! Have ya dead cue ha inu ichae, on the water's edge—
恋のリズムに 狂って
Going wild to the rhythm of love,
弱音だって もう一階一緒につくの センセーション 抱きしめて
Even if I whine, let's create a sensation together once more, hold me tight!
スーパーハイテンション まだ足りない 祭はもっと夢中にさせて
Super high tension, still not enough! Make this festival even more exciting,
ウルトラハイテンション キミと見つめ合うまま
Ultra high tension, staying locked in your gaze,
ジュウジュー ハイパーハイテンション 改めてね必勝の合図 乗りたいやめば
Hyper high tension, a winning signal renewed—if you want to ride it, stop!
ミラクルハイテンション ほどき合ってキューピッド
Miracle high tension, untangling, Cupid!
ほら 弾けそうな胸の鼓動 ちゃんとつかまえてね
Look, catch the beating of my ready-to-burst heart properly!
チェリーは 電波に お願い
Cherry, a request to the radio waves—
見こなの 甘い 届けたいな キミのもとへ
I want to deliver this sweet view to your side!
ソルソル もう一回 まだまだ足りないぞ
Sol sol, once more, still not enough!
こんなもんじゃないだろ 見くびるな 見せてみろよ
This isn't all there is, don't underestimate me, show me what you've got!
日常は 確信犯だね ぐだうとするとこも いいよ
Everyday life is premeditated, even when you're sluggish, it's fine!
スーパーハイテンション まだ足りない 祭はもっと夢中にさせて
Super high tension, still not enough! Make this festival even more exciting,
ウルトラハイテンション キミと見つめ合うまま
Ultra high tension, staying locked in your gaze!
デュウ ハイパーハイテンション 改めてね必勝の合図 そっと丸暗記して
Dew, hyper high tension, a winning signal renewed, softly memorizing it by heart—
ミラクルハイテンション 重ね合わせたいよ
Miracle high tension, I want to overlap them!
ねえ 桜色の想い
Hey, Sakura-colored feelings...
日常は 確信犯だね ちゃんとつかまえてね
Everyday life is premeditated, catch it properly!
ほら さっきまでとは 違うから 受け止めてよね
Look, it's different from until just now, so accept it!
ふう… ああ、どうだった？
Phew... Ah, how was it?
みこの新客…
Miko's new choreography...
パチパチパチパチ、ありがとう！
*clap clap clap*, thank you!
ダンスもね、覚えたんだよ。
I learned the dance too, you know.
ちょっとまだまだ、ふれぎりですが。
Though I'm still a bit rusty.
でも、この曲は、なんとね、まあ、先日ね、発表された2月のライブで…
But this song, you know... well, the one announced the other day for the February live...
歌う、かも…！
I might sing it...!
なので、この後ね、いつも放送終了後に投稿するので、MVをぜひね、見てほしいなと…
So after this, since it'll be posted right after the stream, I hope you'll watch the MV...
思います！あの日付もね、覚えてほしい。よろしくね！
Please remember the date too! Thank you!
ふう… 緊張した…！
Phew... I was so nervous...!
ということでね、今日は皆さん見に来てくれてありがとうございます！
And with that, thank you everyone for coming to watch today!
お待たせしました！告知です、やったー！
Thanks for waiting! It's announcement time, yay!
ニュー衣装でね、みこの、新しいこのかわいいね、まっすぐな、さらにさらにエリートな姿になることも、とっても楽しみだったんですが…
With my new outfit, I was looking forward to becoming even more elite and cute...
この告知を出すのもね、すごくすごく楽しみだったんだよー！やったよー！
I was also super, super excited to make this announcement! Yay!
同じくらいだね。はい。ということで、まず早速ね、まずはこちら、先ほど歌わしていただいた、さくら色ハイテンション！
So first, straight away, first is the song I just sang, "Sakura-iro High Tension!"
じゃじゃーん！いえい！こちらね、新しいオリジナル曲、えっと、セカンドじゃ、サードじゃなくてサド？サド合ってる？スリー？サード！サードシングル「さくら色ハイテンション」こちらね、あのね…
Ta-da! Yay! Third single "Sakura-iro High Tension," this one, you know...
見てよ！分かる人には分かる！またエロゲっぽい曲が…！そう、ですので皆さん、ありがとうございます、聴いてくださってありがとうございます！
Look at this! Those who know, know! Another eroge-style song... Thank you for listening!
ね、すごいんでしょ。よみんのびっくりしてるのも、びっくりするでしょうね。このチームはびっくりするでしょうね！
Right, isn't it amazing? Everyone's going to be so surprised, right? This team too!
ということでね、まあ、エロゲというか、やりゲというか、美少女ゲームというか、まあ、そんな感じでね、あのオープニングっぽい感じで、作らせてもらいました。本当にありがとうございます！
Like an eroge, visual novel, or bishoujo game opening theme, I got to make it. Thank you!
こちらは、まあ後日配信されますのでね、そちらの音声もまたやりたいと思うので、お楽しみによろしくお願いします！
This will be released later, and I want to play through the voice lines too, look forward to it!
そして、見て。分かる人にはわかる。このイラスト… 何かに似てないか？いや、知らない人は知らないと思うんですけど、でもね、みこにとってはすごくすごく嬉しいんです！続いての… お知らせは…！
And look. Those who know, know. Doesn't this illustration look like something? The next announcement is...!
いやあ、こちらだ…！どどん！あれ？ こちらグッズプレ… グッズプレゼントなんだけど…
Oh man, it's this...! Ta-da! Huh? It's a merch presentation, but...
あ、あ、あそこ… あ、あ、あそこ… あーっ！はい、さくらみこ、なんと！ノベルゲーム化企画、「さくら色 DREAMEЯ」…！
Yes, Sakura Miko, what do you know! A visual novel project, "Sakura-iro DREAMEЯ"!
企画がフライングしましたよ！「さくら色 DREAMEЯ」というタイトルです。こちらはね、あの記念グッズ全部セットとして、あの楽曲と、さくら色 DREAMEЯ 特製ボックス、ま、エロゲ箱ですね。はい、と、さくら色 DREAMEЯ 立ち絵…
It's titled "Sakura-iro DREAMEЯ", available as an all-in-one commemoration merch set with special box and standee!
ということでね、こちらはなんとクリスマスにゲームデータが配信、え、開始ということで、皆さん、みこからのクリスマスプレゼント…！嬉しいかな？こまじすごいよ。あの、なんとですね、お手伝いしてくださったのは、みこのだ、だ、だいすきな、みこじゃ一番好きなライブなんですかって言われたら、ああ、歩くことの「クローバーデイズ」ですって言うぐらいの一番好きで一番思い入れが深い、なぜなら、みこがエロゲをハマるきっかけのゲームだから。「クローバーデイズ」を作ってる、アルコットさんに、お手伝いしていただいて、なんとノベルゲーム、作っていただけたんです！ありがとうございます…！
Game data releases on Christmas! Alcot, creators of "Clover Day's", made it for me! Thank you!
シナリオも、本当に素晴らしくて、
The scenario is honestly so wonderful,
まあ前回ね、あの、まあ、あのボイスドラマでも何かさせていただいたりしてね、
and previously, we even got to do a voice drama together,
あのソラシトさんにシナリオを書いていただいて、たくさんシステムもやってもらって、
where Sorashito-san wrote the script and helped set up lots of systems—
すごいでしょう！すごいでしょう！やったやった！
isn't that amazing?! Isn't that amazing?! We did it!
はい、ということで、こちらが、えっと、受注開始はですね、まあ今日からなんですけれども、ゲームデータのみは25日にプレゼント！プレゼント！ということで、
Right! So, pre-orders for this start today, but the game data alone will be delivered as a Christmas present on the 25th!
お楽しみに！ぜひこっちも買ってね！文字すごいから！はーい！
Look forward to it! Make sure to grab this one too, because the word count is huge! Yay!
ということでね、なんとなんと、
And what's more...
はい、じゃあ、その最後もありますからね、気になるでしょ？見に行ってよ、見に行ってくださいよー！
Right, there's also the final reveal, so you're curious, right? Go check it out, please go see it!
ちょっと小さっ！小さっ！小さっこれ！
Oh, it's so small! So small! So small, this!
あ、オッケーオッケーありがとうありがとう！はーい！
Ah, okay, okay, thanks, thanks! Yay!
こちらがね、立ち絵となっております。むっちゃかわいい！そして同じポーズをしていただいた！
This is the standing illustration. Super cute! And they even struck the exact same pose!
みこ用の新しいね、あ、これが公式のあれになるのかな？はい、こちらはみこのね、
Miko's new... oh, is this going to be the official version? Yes, this is Miko's...
スーパーエリート新モデルのアクリルスタンドが、2種類アクリルスタンドがついてくるでしょ！
Acrylic stands in the new "Super Elite" model! You get two kinds of acrylic stands!
はい、そして特製ボックス！じゃじゃーん！マジ神！マジ神なのだよ！
Yes, and the special box! Ta-da! Seriously god-tier! Seriously god-tier!
で、これね、なんでね知ってる人いるって言ったかっていうと、このね、イラストはね、みこの大好きなクロクロレイズのみこが一番好きな、あのイラストのね、同じ立ち絵というか、もう、感動してください、知ってる方は。
And why did I say some of you might know this? Because this illustration is based on the exact same standing pose as one of my favorite illustrations from Kurokuro Rays, which I love the most. So if you know, please be moved!
そして、サクラ色Dreamerのキービジュアル、こっちはね、ゲームに出てくるイラストなわけです！ゲーム内のCGを使用式にさせていただきました。だってかわいいんだもん！かわいいんだもん！
And the key visual for "Sakura-iro Dreamer"—this one is the illustration that appears in the game! We used the in-game CG for the shikishi. Because it's so cute! So cute!
そう！ということで、じゃじゃーん！うわあ、うれしい！みこが一番うれしいよ！ありがとうございます！こんな感じ！わーい！
That's right! So, ta-da! Wow, I'm so happy! Miko is the happiest one! Thank you so much! Like this! Yay!
続いては、えっと、どうぞ。え、続いてはないのか？あ、続いてはないんだ。でも、
Next is... go ahead. Oh, is there nothing next? Ah, nothing next. But,
まだお知らせがあります！なんと、みこちゃんのね、あの、このね、いつも着てる衣装と、
there's still another announcement! Guess what? Miko-chan's... um, this usual outfit of mine,
で、まあ、あのさっきのコーナーにも出てきたね、みこの初期衣装！どっちも、どっちもMMD、はい、実装されます！今日から！
and also Miko's starter outfit that appeared in the earlier segment—both, both MMD versions are being implemented! Starting today,
23日から！やったね！みこのことたくさん応援してください！えっちなのには使わないでください！
from the 23rd! Yay! Please support Miko a lot! Please don't use it for lewd stuff!
あの、下にちゃんとスパッツ入ってるんで。はーい！
Well, there are proper spats underneath. Yep!
ということで、たくさんたくさんね、いろんなね、あのポーズさせたり、踊らせたり、写真撮ったりしてくださーい！やったよー！
So please have fun making me do lots of different poses, dancing, and taking pictures! Yay!
で、ホロメンの今公開されたホロメンの皆とも踊れるんだ、みこやったよ！ねえ、ありがとうございます！
And you can dance with the Holomembers whose 3D models were just released too! Miko did it! Hey, thank you so much!
はい、ということでね、おしらせはこんな感じでございます。はい。
Right, so that's all for the announcements. Yes.
ということで、みんな、まあ、活動してね、もうホロライブに入ったもう2年、12月のね、ここらへんの時期に、ホロライブ加入したからね、あっという間だな、あれ？
So everyone, you know, being active, it's already been two years since I joined Hololive around this time in December, so time really flies, huh? Wait,
あ、3年、ん？どのくらいにも、そうして、ねえ！
Ah, 3 years? Hmm, how long has it really been? Right!
あっというまだね、2周年か！ということでね、新しいみこのこと好きになってくれますか？どうどう？どうどう？
Time really flies, it's 2 years! So, will you come to love the new Miko? How is it? How is it?
うれしかった？みんな。かわいい？たくさんスクショ撮ってくれた？
Were you happy, everyone? Cute? Did you take lots of screenshots?
スクショ撮って、ここにね、ツイートしてね！うん。よかった、よかった、続けてよかった、ホロライブ！ありがとね！ねえ、ありがとうございます！
Take screenshots and tweet them here! Yep. I'm so glad I kept going with Hololive! Thank you! Hey, thank you so much!
まあね、新しくね、みこのことを好きになってくれるみんなも、ずっとね、みこのいろんなね、姿から応援してくれた、みんなも、これからもね、一緒にまた、
And for everyone who has newly grown to love Miko, and everyone who has supported me through my various forms, let's continue to walk together...
来年も！来年もずっとずっと一緒に歩んでいきましょう！みかももっともっとエリートなアイドル、そして、
Next year too! Let's walk together forever next year too! Miko will become an even more elite idol, and...
まあ、配信もね、もちろんたくさん、いっぱいやっていって、どんどん成長していきたいと思います！いつも見守ってくれてどうもありがとう！
of course, I want to do lots and lots of streams and keep growing! Thank you so much for always watching over me!
はい！ということで、このあとね、もうすぐクリスマスですから、まあ、んだと、23時半から配信もありますからね、こちらもぜひ見に来てください！ということで、みんな、今日はどうもありがとうございました！
Yes! So, after this, since it's almost Christmas, well, there's also a stream starting at 23:30, so please come check that out too! And with that, everyone, thank you so much for today!
そして、応援たくさんありがとう！それではみんな、いきますよー！せーの！おつみこー！
And thank you so much for all your support! Alright everyone, here we go! Ready, set! Otsumiko!
3Dお披露目
3D Reveal